Balázs Zsolt KERESZTURY

(+36) 702058525 | balazs.keresztury@protonmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/balazs-keresztury/

https://github.com/belidzs

About me: Experienced System Architect with a demonstrated history of working in the computer software industry. Skilled in Databases, Business Intelligence, Software Development, Network Administration, and Computer Network Operations. Strong engineering professional with a Master of Science (MSc) focused in Business Information Systems from Corvinus University of Budapest. Member of Mensa International.

WORK EXPERIENCE

31/05/2021 – CURRENT – Budapest, Hungary
SOFTWARE DEVELOPER – MORGAN STANLEY HUNGARY ANALYTICS LLC

16/11/2020 - 20/03/2021 - Budapest, Hungary

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER - ORACLE GLOBAL SERVICES HUNGARY LLC

Software Development of a Cloud Native Software-as-a-Service (SaaS) application:

- Python
- ∘ flask
- pandas
- kubernetes (cluster configuration, deployment and scaling)
- GitLab CI/CD (continuous integration pipelines)

Application: Scalable, microservices-based application which makes heavy use of containerization technologies (docker), configuration-as-code (kubernetes) and automated deployment tools (GitLab CI/CD)

Project management methodology: Scrum (Agile)

01/08/2006 – 15/11/2020 – Budapest, Hungary

SYSTEM ARCHITECT - SOLE PROPRIETOR

- IT consulting
- Custom software engineering
- Requirements analysis
- Application integration with existing ERP systems
- Building and maintaining company Data Warehouse

Technologies: .NET C#, Python, Django, flask, PostgreSQL (with PL/pgSQL), Microsoft SQL Server, DevExpress WinForms, Devart for dotConnect, Ubuntu Linux, bash, ansible, Pentaho

14/08/2014 - 14/09/2016 - Budapest, Hungary

NETWORK ENGINEER - CORVINUS UNIVERSITY OF BUDAPEST - CENTER FOR INFORMATION SERVICES

- Had full responsibility over the complete structured IT network
- Deployed new network segments (wired and wireless)
- Operated VoIP and PBX phone centers
- Managed development projects
- Implemented new internal processes (ticketing, source control and other productivity enhancement tools)

14/09/2006 - 14/06/2013 - Budapest, Hungary

SENIOR TEACHING ASSISTANT - CORVINUS UNIVERSITY OF BUDAPEST - INSTITUTE OF INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

Responsibilities:

- Teaching classes
- Organizing exams
- Creating course syllabuses and teaching materials
- Managing junior teaching assistants' work

Taught subjects:

- Database Systems (Oracle)
- Applied Computer Science Databases (MS Access)
- Informatics (MS Excel with VBA scripting)

01/11/2009 - 31/08/2010 - United Kingdom

LOCAL EXPERT IN EMEA WEB ROLLOUT PROJECT - ADT FIRE AND SECURITY PLC

- Assisted in the roll out of an international web project (EMEA region)
- Analysed requirements for different regions
- Provided technical support
- Gave general consulting

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

14/09/2004 - 15/06/2009 - Budapest, Hungary

MASTER AND BACHELOR IN BUSINESS INFORMATION SYSTEMS - Corvinus University of Budapest

IT and economic studies on Business Informatics major

17/08/2008 – 17/01/2009 – Jönköping, Sweden

ERASMUS EXCHANGE STUDENT - Jönköping International Business School

Interaction Design, Knowledge Management, ISD Projects Development, Swedish language

01/09/2011 - 30/06/2013 - Budapest, Hungary

CISCO CERTIFIED NETWORK ASSOCIATE - CCNA (COURSE ONLY) - Corvinus University of Budapest

Attended course and passed final exam. No certification was awarded.

Ability to install, configure, operate, and troubleshoot medium-size routed and switched networks, including implementation and verification of connections to remote sites in a WAN.

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): HUNGARIAN

Other language(s):

| | UNDERSTANDING | | SPEAKING | | WRITING |
|---------|---------------|---------|-------------------|--------------------|---------|
| | Listening | Reading | Spoken production | Spoken interaction | |
| ENGLISH | C1 | C1 | C1 | C1 | C1 |
| GERMAN | B2 | B2 | B2 | B2 | B2 |
| SPANISH | B2 | B2 | B2 | B2 | B2 |
| SWEDISH | A1 | A2 | A1 | A1 | A1 |

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

NETWORKS AND MEMBERSHIPS

31/03/2011 - CURRENT

Member of Mensa International

Membership ID: 12794 (HU)

DRIVING LICENCE

Driving Licence: A **Driving Licence:** B

PROJECTS

Open-source software development

Maintainer of the following projects with OSI approved licenses:

- PreciseLM35 (Arduino library for LM35 temperature sensor)
- MailgunAddressValidator (C# library for checking e-mail addresses using Mailgun's online service)
- HungarianBankAccount (C# library to check validity of GIRO bank account numbers)
- Various Chocolatey packages
- beancount_mnb (Python module for beancount plain text personal accounting software)
- gnucash_quotes (Python script to download stock prices into GnuCash personal accounting software)

Contributor to other projects:

- home-assistant (home automation platform)
- Signal-Android (encrypted messaging app for Android)
- Signal-Desktop (encrypted messaging app for electron)
- AdAway (ad filtering for Android)
- Loop Habits (habit tracker on Android)
- FaceSlim (Facebook client on Android)
- zeyple (GPG encryption for postfix)
- git-for-windows (SCM client on Windows)

ORGANISATIONAL SKILLS

Freelancing

Being a freelancer software engineer taught me how to:

- Continuously improve my skills
- Understand business requirements
- Mediate between conflicting interests

Teaching assistant

As senior teaching assistant I was responsible for 3-5 junior teaching assistants' performance. This experience helped me to gain leadership skills through the following tasks:

- Organizing and leading weekly teachers' meetings
- QA of teaching
- Exam organization
- Writing teaching materials
- Escalating and negotiating problems and special requests to the Head of Department